and this personality test costs 29 yuan.
这个人格测试呢29块钱啊
Of course, when we talk about any psychological test,
当然来讲咱们说任何心理测试
or IQ test
智商测试
Personality tests shouldn’t be done so casually.
人格测试都不能用这么草率的方法啊
Selecting a few questions won’t give you accurate results.
选几道题就测出来了
This thing isn’t reliable.
这个东西不准
If you want to test your personality,
如果你想去测人格
test your genes,
测基因
or for the best IQ test, go to a hospital.
测智商最好的话是去医院啊
Doing a test that costs a few thousand dollars,
做一个几千块钱的题
that one tends to be more accurate.
那个东西啊会文的会比较准一点哈
This personality test is also something like that.
这个人格测试呢也是一个啊
I knew what the outcome would be.
我知道会是什么结果
So I deliberately played it that way.
所以我就故意那么打啊
Everyone can see that my test result indicates I have a narcissistic personality.
大家看到我的测试结果是我是自恋型人格
Combined with antisocial and histrionic personality traits.
加这个反社会人格加表演型人格啊
Of course, to put it bluntly,
当然来讲的话
these three personality types are what people despise as scum.
这三种人格就是人人唾弃的人渣人格
But in practice,
但是在实际操作中呢
you'll find in Chinese society,
你会发现在中国社会当中
these three types, or a combination of them,
这三种人或者说这三种人合成的啊
This kind of person is rather indifferent. But they make themselves very comfortable. Such people will never become depressed. Why is that? Let me tell you. Because a narcissistic personality, it creates a particularly strong shield for their confidence.
这种人来讲的话是浑浑淡淡的 但是呢却让自己很舒服啊 这种人永远不会抑郁啊 为什么呢 我跟你讲 因为自恋型人格呢 他会对自信心产生一种特别强大的防护
Everything is always someone else's fault.
一切都是别人的错啊
Trump is just such a person.
特朗普就是这样的人
An antisocial personality, as long as they respect the rule of law
反社会型人格呢哈只要他啊尊重法治啊
can be a law-abiding citizen
是一个守法公民啊
and there won’t be much of an issue
就不会有太大的问题
But what’s a characteristic of an antisocial personality?
但是反社会型人格是有一个什么样的特点呢
It’s the tendency to use mental or physical strength to challenge authority
就是会用自己的精神力量或者是肉体的力量去对抗权威啊
to defy everyone
就是谁也不服啊
This is what’s known as a reactive personality
这就反射性人格啊
an antisocial personality
反社会人格
And when it comes to a histrionic personality
然后说到这个表演型人格上来讲的话
You'll encounter all sorts of obstacles in reality
就是你会遇到现实当中遇到各种障碍
all kinds of enemies
各种敌人
all sorts of people
各种各样的人啊
who doubt you
质疑你的
who slander you
诋毁你的
you just brush it off
你呢就是当无所谓啊
with a grin
嬉皮笑脸啊
yeah, sure
对对对啊
to deal with such people
去对付这样的人啊
Smoothly dodging all these attacks
圆滑的去对躲开这一切的攻击
So you love to act
所以呢你又爱演
And this person also likes to plot against others
然后呢又反这个人又喜欢谋反
And you’re narcissistic
然后呢你又自恋
This will provide excellent protection for your personal image To deal with a boss with NPD A parent with NPD You have to become like them Just as narcissistic as they are
就会对你的人格外形有一种非常良好的保护啊 想对付NPD型老板 NPD型家长 你只有变得跟他一样啊 变得跟他一样的自恋啊
Violence
暴力啊
It becomes more, how to say, sophisticated
又变得比较的那个怎么说呢
You become more cautious and cunning
自我会防护又会变得比较狡猾
This is the safest approach
这个是最安全的
Like Jia Xu and Sima Yi working for Cao Cao
就像贾诩啊和司马懿给曹操打工
When you're facing a boss like Cao Cao
你面对曹操这样的老板
What can you do about it?
你能该怎么办呢
Right?
对不对
You have to be even more calculating
你只能比他更加的处心积虑
More sinister
更加的阴险
Because he is a very suspicious person
因为他就是一个很多疑的人
But this person has a good side
但是这个人有好的一面
Right?
对不对
Unifying the three kingdoms was the foundation he laid
统一了三国是他打下的基础
Rong’s personality often avoids situations that would make me depressed
荣哥这种人格就经常不会遇到让我郁闷的事情
Because once something goes wrong
因为一旦出了什么问题
I’m definitely the first to point out others’ mistakes
我一定是先挑别人的错
I would never look for reasons within myself
我绝对不会在自身上找原因啊
Unless it's something only I can do
除非这个东西只有我一个人啊
if there's an outcome
产生了结果
or if I don’t collaborate with anyone then I would attribute it to bad timing haha, it must be that the heavens don't want me to make a move right now don't want me to suffer a setback so speaking of luck
或者我不与任何人合作 这个时候我就会归于时运不佳 哈哈一定是这个老天爷现在不想让我啊出击 不想让我受折损 所以来讲才运气这么样
if it's bad, I would attribute it to luck
不好我就会归功于运气了
so I will never blame myself for everything
所以我永远不会把一切的原因归于自己身上啊
Today I was chatting with a friend.
就我今天我跟一个朋友聊天
He's a classic example of something.
就是他呢就是典型的什么呢
A classic self-destructive personality.
典型的自毁型人格啊
Recently, during a job hunt,
他就是啊最近招聘的时候呢
he encountered a boss who seemed like a scammer.
遇到了一个疑似骗子的老板
The boss’s company looked quite suspicious,
因为这个老板的公司呢看起来很奇怪
and he’s not even the legal representative.
自己又不是法人啊
Yet, he uses the company to engage in all sorts of fraudulent activities.
然后拿着这个公司呢进行各种各样的招摇撞骗
So, he suspects this person is a scammer.
所以他呢就怀疑这个人是骗子
Then it escalated into a verbal fight.
后来跟对方对骂起来了
I told him,
我就跟他说
There's no need to engage in a shouting match.
你没有必要对骂
Just stay calm and do nothing.
你就按兵不动就完了
Just ignore the person.
就不要去理这个人就完了啊
But he still ended up arguing with the other person.
然后他呢就跟对方对骂
Later, it turned out that the other person might not have been a scammer after all.
后来呢事后呢又发现对方呢可能不是骗子
Of course, I still think the other person was a scammer.
当然我觉得对方是骗子啊
He felt like he had offended the wrong person.
他就是觉得哎哟又得罪错人了
draining oneself over and over again
又反复的消耗自己
and then wondering if you've offended someone feeling that the day is just ruined in fact, all these personality traits you'll eventually realize they are merely tools for exploitation survival tools not something that exists innately
然后又觉得自己是不是得罪人了 然后觉得自己这一天就过不好了 其实呢所有的这人的这人格呢 最后你会发现它只是一种利用来的啊 生存工具 他不是一个天生就存在的东西
let's talk about Western psychological analysis
咱们说西方的心理学分析啊
and sociological theories
社会学这些东西
It has its own flaws as well.
它本身也有一定的瑕疵
So don't regard these personality types
所以你不要把这些人格类型啊
or these tendencies
把这些倾向
or the various traumas from different so-called family backgrounds
把这些不同的这种所谓的原生家庭的各种各样的创伤呢
as if they were the end of the world.
就看作是一个天大的事啊
For instance, for those of us who are more narcissistic
你像我们比较自恋的人来讲的话
we have an unshakeable confidence.
有绝对不可磨损的自信心
This unshakeable confidence is incredibly vital in today's society.
这个不可磨损的自信心在现代社会中来讲非常的重要啊
Once your confidence can be easily shaken by others
一旦你的自信心会被别人轻易打击
Others will definitely criticize him
别人就一定会打击他
That's how it is
就是这样
So if you have this extremely narcissistic personality
所以如果你有这种非常自恋的人格来讲的话
Your confidence is basically in an unshakable state
你的自信心基本就是无法磨损的一个状态
I am a legend
嗯我就是一个传奇
Everything is always someone else's fault
一切都是别人的错
So paradoxically, it can lead to success
所以反而就容易通向成功啊
It can also lead down the path of being a scoundrel
容易通向无赖之路
Because in this society
因为在这个社会当中
There are plenty of hypocrites In our Chinese society, what prevails is the traditional Confucian morality Many people appear to be morally upright on the surface But they do all sorts of dirty deeds behind the scenes
伪君子最多 咱们的中国社会当中最多的就是儒家的那种传统道德 很多人就是啊表面上仁义道德 背地里坏事肮脏事做尽
Yet everyone is eager to put on a show
但是人人都愿意表演
Because in this context
因为在这个地方来讲的话
Moral performance artists are the most popular
道德表演技术家是最吃香的
Don't believe me? Just look at Zong Qinghou
不信你就看宗庆后是不是就是这样
You must always fly economy class
你呢一定得坐经济舱啊
Not a single cent should be given to foreigners
一分钱也不能给外国人
Look how well the performance is
你看表演的多好啊
But in the end, it turns out all the kids are foreigners
结果最后实际呢啊孩子全是外国人
We can talk about these things
这些事情咱们就说啊
All these things are talk without action
所有这些事情就是说的不会做
Those who do can't talk
做的不会说啊
It's always like this
都是这样
Then look at antisocial personalities
然后你再看反社会人格
You'll find that in reality, many people use their power to suppress others, right
你会发现现实当中有很多人用权势来压你是吧
He uses his experience to overpower you
用他的经验来压你
He uses his gender to overpower you
用他的性别来压你
But in reality, it's all nonsense
实际呢狗屁不是
Right?
对不对
It's all nonsense
狗屁不是啊
Traditional society gives you all sorts of things
传统社会给了你各种各样的东西
Making you think you're really something
让你认为自己很厉害
But in fact, you're nothing
其实你狗屁都不是啊
So if you have antisocial personality disorder
所以如果你有反社会人格呢
You won’t be intimidated by any authority
你就不会对任何什么权威
or leaders
什么领导
or power
什么什么权利
You’re nobody, how can you command me? Can you really command me? Isn’t it clear that we’re not in the same system? How can you command me? Right? If you command me, I won’t comply
你狗屁都不是你指挥的了我吗啊你指挥的了我吗 是不是我跟你首先就不是一个系统的 你怎么指挥我 对不对 你指挥我我就不干了
I’ll just leave this system
我就退出这个系统
Weren't you insulting me in the group?
你不是在群里骂我吗
Either I kick you out
要么我就给你踢了
Or I leave the group
要么我就退这个群
It's that simple
就这么简单
For me, leaving the group is all it takes
对我退群就完了
Right?
是不是
So often it's like this
所以很多时候就是这样
The more antisocial you are
你越反社会啊
The less society can do to you
这社会越不能奈何你啊
So it might not be such a bad thing.
所以来讲未必是件坏事
Antisocial personality.
反社会人格
As long as you don't kill.
只要你别杀
Don't commit murder or arson.
别杀人放火
Generally speaking, there's not much of an issue.
一般来讲没有什么太大问题啊
Now, let's talk about histrionic personality.
再说表演型人格
Do you think there's nothing in this society that doesn't need to be acted out?
你觉得这社会中很多东西不需要演吗
Actually, if you tell the truth,
实际如果你说实话的话
Do you think many people can accept it?
你看很多人接受得了吗
Bro Rong often tells the truth
荣哥就经常说实话
Bro Rong often gets scolded
荣哥就经常挨骂
Some people just can't handle the truth
你说实话有些人是接受不了的
But your core true followers are acceptable.
但是你的核心真爱粉丝算是能接受的
However, when it comes to the general public
但是对于面面对的芸芸众生的时候
Do you really need to speak your mind?
你用得着说真话吗
Speaking the truth comes at a cost
说真话是有代价的
So most of the time
所以大部分时候来讲
You just say something vague
你就是说模棱两可的话
Speaking half-truths
你说半真半假的话
is the safest way to go
这样的东西讲是最安全的
So when talking about narcissistic personality
所以来讲虽说啊自恋型人格
antisocial personality combined with histrionic personality is a really messed-up combination but in reality, it works What is pragmatism? Pragmatism is about what works effectively. without suffering Look at how many people can't handle life and end up taking their own lives
反社会人格加表演型人格是一种非常操蛋的一种组合 但是在现实当中它就是实用啊 实用主义是什么 实用主义就是这个东西行之有效啊 不受罪 你看现实中现在有多少人想不开自杀
Right?
对不对
How many people feel anxious because they can't do certain things well?
有多少人因为一些事情做不好焦虑
How many people are trapped in obsessive thoughts?
有多少人陷于强迫症的考虑当中
How many people have a people-pleasing personality?
有多少人是讨好型人格
How many people have a confrontational personality?
有多少人是反驳型人格
It's that scary.
就是这么可怕啊
There's no benefit at all.
没有任何好处
He just has to do these things.
他就要做这些事
Why?
为什么
Because Confucian thinkers
因为儒家思想家
the school system has solidified his mindset
学生学校这个系统他就给他固化了
these ideas
就这些思想
he has a mindset of an employee
他就是一个打工人的思维
it's a lower-level mindset
就是底层思维
so he can't advance
所以他没有办法往上走
it's that simple
就这么简单
when you have the mindset of a boss
当你是一个老板的思维
when you're in a superior position
当你是一个人上人的状态的时候
your presence and aura are different from others
你的状态气场都跟别人不一样啊
you attract the opposite sex
你吸引异性
and this has nothing to do with other factors
而且这个东西来讲跟一些什么其他东西无关
many people are quite simple
很多人很很简单
relying on physical attractiveness when young
年轻的时候靠一些色相
thinking it can attract others
觉得能吸引别人
but as you get older
你再大一点岁数呢
can you rely on money?
你不靠钱行吗
can you rely on power?
你不靠权势行吗
without these things
没有这些东西的
to navigate society
所以在这个社会中混来讲
be a bit narcissistic a bit antisocial even a bit performative half-truths are the safest never feel guilty about your personality flaws let others be the ones to suffer
自恋一点啊 反社会一点 甚至表演一点 半真半假是最安全的 永远不要因为自己的人格操蛋而觉得内疚 让别人去难过